人类就是自私
To be human is to be self-involved.
每个人都相信自己是宇宙中心
Everyone believes they're the center of the universe.
我们忍不住
We can't help it.
这是我们的天性
It's in our nature.
我们谋划 盘算
We scheme, we plot.
我们玩我们的小游戏
We play our silly little games.
我们为何认为自己是世界上最重要的
Like, why do we think we're the most important thing in the world?
我们不是
We're just not.
我明白一件大部分人不敢承认的事
See, I understand something most people are afraid to admit.
宇宙是冷漠的
The universe is indifferent.
它不在乎我们的小破计划
It doesn't care about our stupid, little plans
或是我们脆弱的小心脏
or our fragile, little hearts.
宇宙对我们有自己的安排
The universe has its own plans for us...
登上雪国列车
aboard Snowpiercer,
1001节车厢
1,001 cars long.
雪国列车
第一季 第七集
莱顿知道了
Layton knows,
而他就在附属列车里自由行走
and he's just running around the subtrain.
我觉得他在躲藏 他会被发现的
I think he's hiding out and he'll be found.
我们应该坦白
I think we should come clean.
告诉乘客们这里只有我们三个
We'll tell the passengers it's just the three of us up here
或是在莱顿发话前说点什么
or tell them something before Layton does.
他们很快就会把我们的脑袋推出舱门
They'd have our heads out of a port in no time.
莱顿也不会说的
And Layton isn't gonna leak it,
至少现在还不会
not yet anyway.
你怎么能确定
How could you be so sure?
我觉得他会握着这个秘密
I think he's gonna control his secret
直到他想到怎么用最好
till he knows the best way to use it --
但我不会放任他的
only I'm not gonna let him.
列车交给你 哈维
You have the train, Javi.
列车交给我
I have the train.
各位乘客注意
Attention all passengers.
威尔福德工业祝您早上好
Wilford Industries wishes you good morning.
昨天 在托雷塔峡谷危机期间
Yesterday, during the Torreta Canyon Crisis,
电力工程师彼得·迪马科
Electrical Engineer Peter DiMarco
为了我们的存活牺牲了自己
paid the ultimate price for our survival.
让我们为他的灵魂默哀片刻吧
Let us all observe a moment for his spark.
万物必生长
As crops must grow,
会有新血液流入
new blood will flow.
依照惯例
So as is our custom,
我们现在将宣布接替学徒
we will now announce an apprentice replacement.
今天 这项最大殊荣
Today, the greatest of honors --
被称为"定心丸"的男孩
the young man known as Miles and Miles
将被直接送入火车头
will be fast-tracked to the Engine!
好样的 迈尔斯
Well done, Miles.
Great job, Miles.
-感谢你的信念和劳动 -迈尔斯
- Thank you for your faith and your labors. - Miles.
一如既往 我们伟大的工程师 威尔福德先生
As always, our Great Engineer, Mr. Wilford,
祝您一天愉快
wishes you a pleasant day.
你提拔他有点太快了吧 梅兰妮
You're pushing him up that ladder a bit too fast, aren't Melanie?
怎么回事
What's going on?
你今天休息 露丝
It's your day off, Ruth.
喘口气吧
Take a break.
-这是陷阱 -当然是了
- It's a trap, Josie. - Yeah, of course it's a trap.
-但如果他去了火车头 -那我们做到了
- But if he's in the Engine... - Well, then we did it, right?
终于有车尾人进入了火车的神经中枢
We finally got a Tailie right into the nerve center of the train.
那部分感觉很真实 是吧
That part does feel true, doesn't it?
她把他留在身边 是人质也是诱饵
Well, she'll keep him close -- hostage and bait.
你不能去见他 乔茜
You can't see him, Josie.
我知道你很想 但梅兰妮的目标是我
I know you want to, but Melanie is coming for me, alright?
我们得把握每一秒的时间
We need to spend every free second
动员三等厢奋起反抗
trying to move Third to the cause.
是 你是要发动三等厢
Yeah, you have to turn Third,
但我们也得联系上迈尔斯
but we have to make contact with Miles, too.
我还有三个小时
I've got three hours.
你确定只有他一个人失踪了
And you're sure he's the only one missing?
我做了全面清点
I-I did a complete inventory.
他不可能凭一己之力逃出去
He couldn't have gotten out on his own.
你上一次检查莱顿
When did you last check Layton --
真正看到他是什么时候
actually lay on eyes on him?
-审判那天 -两天前吗
- The day of the trial. - Two days ago?
所以他逃走的时间是在审判当天
So he got out sometime between then
到昨天与我对峙之前
and when he confronted me yesterday.
肯定有人帮他逃跑
Then someone helped him escape.
清点时还有别的发现
The inventory found something else.
有几袋假死药不见了
There are several bags of suspension drugs missing.
是哪里的清洁工作没做好吗
Is there a janitorial problem?
真有意思
Funny.
你知道在威尔福德先生的列车上
Do you know the punishment for trafficking drugs
走私毒品会遭到何种惩罚吗
on Mr. Wilford's train?
一只手臂
An arm.
-习惯用的那一侧 -吃饭用的那只手
- Dominant side. - The hand that feeds.
或者是给列车提供克洛诺的那只手
Or the hand that supplies the train with Kronole.
帮助囚犯安德烈·莱顿
The hand that helped a prisoner named Andre Layton
逃离抽屉的那只手
escape from The Drawers --
我猜是想以此交换假死药 来制造
I'm guessing in exchange for suspension drugs to make
克洛诺
said Kronole.
我对这件事一无所知
I don't know anything about that.
你知道
You know,
我现在关心的不是毒品
it's not the drugs that I care about right now.
我还是不知道你在说什么
Doesn't change what I know.
你是右撇子吧
You're right-handed?
戒指不错
Nice ring.
作为抹地的清洁员 你手上没什么老茧啊
Not very calloused for a mop-and-bucket guy, are you?
好吧
Alright.
我见过莱顿一次
I met Layton once --
五六个星期前 搏击赛那晚
five, six weeks ago, the night of the fight.
他找我询问谋杀案的事
He came to me and asked me about the murders,
我给了他一些情报
and I gave him some information,
仅此而已
and -- and that's all.
特伦斯...
Terence...
就说这么点连根手指都救不了
that's not enough to save a finger.
听我说
Look.
我可以帮你
I can help you.
如果他正在逃亡 他迟早都会来找我
If he's on the run, sooner or later, he's gonna come to me.
到时候我就把他带来给你
And then I'll bring him to you.
准备去工作了
Getting ready for work.
几乎一切正常
It's almost normal.
你忘了安检芯片
Except for the security chip...
几乎
...almost.
你真的好美
You're so damn beautiful.
接我的人马上就到
My ride's on the way.
好的
Okay.
那我们可以走了
Then we're good to go.
小心一点 乔茜
Be careful, Josie.
你更要小心
I want you to be careful.
他们在找的人不是我
They're not looking for me.
伟大的革命者归来了
The great revolutionary returns.
你不拉我一把吗
You gonna give me a hand?
永动机学徒
Engine Apprentice.
这是在雪国列车上最接近上帝的机会
Well, it's the closest one gets to God on "Snowpiercer."
我们都该为迈尔斯感到骄傲
We should all be very proud of our Miles.
今天 我们有幸邀来一位特别的客人
And we are very lucky to have a special guest today --
工程部的班尼特·诺克斯先生
Mr. Bennett Knox from Engineering,
他来协助迈尔斯转调
here to assist with Miles' transition.
谢谢你 吉利斯老师
Thank you, Ms. Gillies.
迈尔斯 为庆祝你的成就
Miles, in honor of your accomplishment,
同学们为你准备了一个特别惊喜
the class has a very special surprise for you.
-太棒了 -好样的 迈尔斯
- Awesome. - Good job, Miles.
吃吧
Dig in.
没错 赶紧吃
That's right. Get right in there.
看起来好好吃
It looks so good.
露丝
Ruthie.
你没穿制服 我差点没认出你
I hardly recognize you out-of-uniform.
我今天休息 诺兰
Ah, it's my day off, Nolan.
我能习惯从喇叭里听见
You know, I could get used to hearing your pretty voice
-你动听的嗓音 -少来了
- over the loudspeaker. - Oh, shush.
就一次而已
That was a one-time thing.
你在危机中所做的
Well, what you did during the crisis,
像那样对全列车的人说话
speaking to the train like that,
是极大的安抚
it was a great comfort.
我们中有很多人对你所做的一切感激不已
There's many of us who appreciate everything you do.
谢了 诺兰
Thanks, Nolan.
我该...
I should probably, uh...
谢谢
Thanks.
露丝
Ruth.
不知道你想不想一起去吃午餐
I wonder if you'd like to go for lunch.
我很愿意
Um, I would like that.
不如就今天
How's today?
如果你休假这天没有约
If your day off isn't spoken for.
今天就挺好
Today would be great.
那我们约好了
Then it's a date.
是你啊
Hey, you.
你怎么会在这儿
What are you doing here?
莱顿逃出来了
Layton got out.
他在列车上任意行动
He's loose on the train.
什么意思
What do you mean?
他从车尾出来了吗
He got out of the Tail?
两晚前你没来 当时你去哪了
Where were you two nights ago when you didn't show up?
我...
I, uh...
我昨晚告诉你了
I told you last night.
我对这一切感到很紧张
I'm nervous about all this.
我在三等厢过夜
I stayed in Third.
贝丝 现在正发生一些你不明白的事
Bess, there are things happening that you don't understand.
如果你知道莱顿在哪 必须立刻告诉我
If you know where Layton is, you need to tell me now.
提尔
Till!
我不知道 好吗
I don't, okay?
我轮班要迟到了
I'm late for my shift.
《一只叫天竺葵的长颈鹿》
"A Giraffe Called Geranium,"
作者是安斯莉·曼森
by Ainslie Manson.
好
Okay.
"在一个温暖的夏日 在加拿大西海岸
"One warm summer day, on the West Coast of Canada,
一只年轻的长颈鹿
a young giraffe steps
你感觉怎么样
How are you getting on?
优雅地跨过苏珊娜家的大门 进入她的花园
gracefully over Susanna's gate and into her garden.
我感觉不太舒服
I don't feel so good.
长颈鹿是她最喜欢的动物
Giraffes were her favorite animal.
她丝毫不介意..."
She didn't even mind..."
你担心要和其他孩子分开 对吗
You're worried about being separated from the other kids, hmm?
朋友 这就是工程师的生活
That, my friend, is the life of an Engineer.
但在那里 我们能看到别人看不到的东西
But, up there, we get to see things nobody else does --
幻日 崩坏
sun dogs and destruction.
放松点
Easy now.
-好了 就这样 -你没事吧
- Okay, that's enough. - You're alright.
有小伙伴不舒服时我们该干什么
What do we do when a child is ill?
-戴口罩 -你们知道章程
- Get a mask on. - You know the drill.
给 传下去 好吗
Here you go. Hand these out, alright?
我要找人来代课
I'm gonna have to get a substitute
马上带他去医务室
and take him to the clinic right away.
好吧 我能跟你去吗
Alright. Will I come with you?
行 戴上这个
Fine. Put that on.
迈尔斯 你会没事的
Miles, you're gonna be okay.
别担心
Don't worry.
来 我们走
Okay, come on. Here we go.
你也了解劳动力关系网 好吗
You know the labor networks, okay?
我需要见几个关键人物
I need to meet a few key people.
你是在让他们参加一场暴乱
You're asking them to join an insurrection,
-让他们抛却生死 -是的
- to lay down their lives. - Yes, I am.
我需要值得信任 训练有素的领导者
I need any trustworthy, train-smart leaders
能够让其他人也参与其中
who can help bring others to the table.
我们为什么要支持你呢
Why should we throw our weight behind you?
你现在在逃 自身都难保
You're on the run. You're a liability.
我知道 奥德丽
I know, Audrey!
我只有短暂的时机
I got a very small window,
但我手上掌握了超乎想象的信息
but I got more pieces than I ever thought possible.
我需要你帮我动员三等厢
I need you to help me move Third.
那你觉得我在审判之后都在做什么
What do you think I've been doing since the trial?
政治活动
Politicking.
对 没错
Yes, that's right.
不见血的战争
War without bloodshed.
我们的总攻本来已经蓄势待发
We were poised for a General Strike.
对 让我猜猜
Yeah, let me guess.
昨天的危机让你失去了声势
Yesterday's crisis stole your thunder?
我也是
Mine, too.
那是梅兰妮·卡维尔的手笔
That was Melanie Cavill.
梅兰妮·卡维尔做了什么
What was Melanie Cavill?
带你能信任的人来见我
Bring me the key people you trust.
我有故事要讲
I got a story to tell.
好了 我们这儿有一个病得很严重的孩子
Alright. Okay, we have a very sick kid here!
-他吐得满屋子都是 -他怎么了
- He barfed clear across the room! - What's wrong with him?
好吧 让我看看你怎么了
Alright. Let's have a look at you.
来吧 来吧 这边
Come on. Come on. Let's go.
让我看看 好
Let's have a look at you. That's it.
从这里过去 过去
Straight through here. There you go.
你进来干嘛
Where do you think you're going?
只是想看着我们最新的工程师
Just keeping an eye on our newest Engineer.
很好 如果他患上传染病
Brilliant. And if he's contagious,
他会让你们整个区都感染
he'll infect your whole department.
别关这个门
Let's keep this open.
我们从这里能看到
We can watch from here.
他不会离开你的视线的
He'll never be out of your sight.
好了 到床上来
Alright. Hop on up there.
靠着枕头 抬起膝盖
Lean back against the pillows, get your knees up.
来看看
Let's take a look.
你好 我的定心丸
Hello, my Miles and Miles.
妈
Mum?
我们得表现得正常点 他才不会注意到
We have to act normal, okay, so he doesn't notice.
你的房间肯定很不错
I bet you have a nice cabin.
你应该看看我见过的事
You should see the things I've seen.
他们会为了逃学不择手段
Oh they'll do anything to get out of school.
不择手段
Anything.
我很抱歉让你生病
I'm sorry I made you sick.
这是我能见到你的唯一方式
It was the only way I could get to see you.
我很想你
I missed you.
我们还得再分开一小段时间
We have to be apart just a little bit longer.
但是听着 革命马上就开始了
But, listen, the revolution is happening.
那样的工作一定很有趣吧...
It must be so interesting working...
莱顿跟我们在一起 他做好了计划
Layton's with us. He's got a plan.
告诉莱顿我准备好了
Tell Layton I'm ready.
好小伙子
Good man.
我们可能不会在革命开始前再跟你见面了
We might not see you before it starts.
我们需要你做一件非常重要的事
There's something really important we need you to do.
与威尔福德先生一起工作是什么感觉
What's it like working with Mr. Wilford?
他是一位非同寻常的人
He's such a fascinating person.
再见 妈妈
Goodbye, Mom.
跟我说说你的火车头吧 说说火车头吧
Oh, tell me about your Engine. Tell me about the Engine!
瞧瞧你啊
Well, look at you.
我们独享了整节车厢
The whole car to ourselves.
有什么不对吗
Something wrong?
不不不 没事
No, no, no. Nothing.
只是我有很长一段时间没...
It's just been a while since I, uh...
约会吗
Dated?
我觉得这难以置信
I find that hard to believe.
雪国列车上可没有多少选择 是吧
Well, there aren't a lot of options on Snowpiercer, are there?
所有人都是成双成对地上车的 不是吗
Everyone boarded two by two, didn't they?
除了我
Except me.
你当时是怎么登上雪国列车的呢
So how did you come to be in Snowpiercer, then?
这个嘛
Ah-ha, well,
在旧世界里 我曾在肯德尔镇经营一家民宿
in the Old World, I had a B&B in Kendal.
一天晚上 狂风暴雨之中 出现了...
And one night, in the middle of this rainstorm, this...
一位奇怪的男人
strange man turned up.
他没有预订 没带行李
He had no reservation, he had no luggage,
全身都被淋透了
he was soaked to the bone,
当时是淡季 所以我就很主动热情地
and it was the off-season, so I took it upon myself
开始照顾他
to look after him, you know --
确保能满足他的所有需求
make sure he had everything he needed,
然后我们开始聊天
and we got to talking.
他告诉我他正在建造的一辆
And he told me all about this fabulous luxury liner
极其豪华的列车
that he was building,
他说他需要像我这样的人
said he needed people just like me,
并且当场给我提供了一个职位
and gave me a job on the spot.
这就是我跟威尔福德先生相识的经过
That's how I met Mr. Wilford.
他找到你是我们的幸运
Well, we're very lucky He found you.
祝他健康
To His health.
His health.
不过我能问你一件事吗 诺兰
Can I ask you something, though, Nolan.
你的妻子两年前就去世了
Your wife died two years ago.
为什么现在才找我
Why now?
我想和你谈话有一段时间了
I wanted to talk to you for a while now.
这是真的
That's the truth.
但我得说实话
But I have to be honest,
这次午餐还有另一个目的
there's another aspect to this luncheon.
露丝 指挥官
Ruth. Commander.
今天是吃鱼的好日子
Perfect day for fish.
很高兴见到你 露丝
It's lovely to see you, Ruth.
我刚才跟罗伯特说
I was just saying to Robert
距离我们上次聊天有好长时间了
it's been too long since we chatted.
是的 没错 有很长时间了
Uh, yes. Well, yes, been a long time.
我们得谈一下事情 露丝
We have to discuss something, Ruthie.
露丝
Ruth...
长话短说 有一些乘客感到
in a nutshell, a number of passengers feel
梅兰妮权力过大
that Melanie has too much power,
她对威尔福德先生有过大的影响
too much influence with Mr. Wilford.
我 我不确定我
Well, I'm -- I'm not sure that I, uh --
我们认为是时候做出改变了
We think it's time for a change.
如果这样的话 你有兴趣站出来吗
If that were to happen, would you be interested in stepping up?
你想要替代梅兰妮
You want to replace Melanie?
如果三等厢都能请愿改变庭审
Well, if Third can petition to change the trial,
我们也可以请愿改变管理部门
we can petition to change management.
好吧 诺兰
Right, Nolan.
-原来你叫我来是因为这个 -露丝
- That's what this is about, is it? - Ruth.
我不太擅长表达我的感受
I don't express my feelings well,
但我说的都是真心话
but I meant what I said.
我唯一考虑这么做的原因是我对你的信心
The only reason I'd even considered this is my faith in you.
好好想想
And just think --
你会和威尔福德先生共事
you'd be working with Mr. Wilford,
那才是属于你的地方
where you belong.
我没兴趣
Hey, I'm not interested!
怎么了
What's going on?
你好
Hello.
我是来跟你谈安德烈的
I'm here to talk about Andre.
莱顿 他不是在车尾吗
Layton? Isn't he in -- in the Tail?
听说你怀孕了
I understand you're pregnant.
恭喜
Congratulations.
这真是好消息
That's wonderful news.
你知道在雪国列车上有孩子是特权吗
You know it's a privilege to have a child on Snowpiercer?
不是基本权利
It's not a right.
而特权
And privileges...
夺走它们跟赐予它们一样容易
well, they can be taken away just as easily as they're given.
所以
So...
是谁帮他逃跑的
...who helped him escape?
莱顿的建议值得被听到 他代表车尾
Layton deserves to be heard. He speaks for the Tail.
我不认识任何车尾人 也不认识你
I don't know any Tailies, and I don't know you.
你的人不会有什么损失
Your people have got nothing to lose.
这里情况不好 但也算是生活
I mean, it's bad up here, but it's a life.
你要打算用什么代替
And what are you gonna replace it with?
听着 莱顿的目的跟我们一致
Look, Layton wants what we want --
没有阶级 没有边境
no classes, no borders.
同工同酬
Equal labor, equal rations.
但车尾人想要空间 要怎么满足
But the Tailies want space. What about that?
我们不会占据你们的床
We are not coming for your beds.
头等厢有保龄球馆
First Class has a bowling alley, okay?
列车上有足够空间分配给所有人
There is plenty of space on this train to go around.
-列车上有300个司闸员和守卫 -是的
- There are 300 Brakemen and Jackboots on this train. - Yes.
从车尾到车头有10英里 上千道门
It's a 10-mile mark from Tail to Engine, thousands of doors.
如果我告诉你那些门都能打开呢
Okay, what if I told you all those doors could be open...
我可以召集一个近400人的军队
that I could bring an army of almost 400
加上我所掌握的信息 我们可以一次性
and, with what I know, we could take down this train
-拿下整辆列车 -那就说出来啊
- in one move. - I'd say spit it out.
因为我掌握的信息我被关进了抽屉
I got thrown in a drawer for what I learned...
关于住在火车头里那人的信息
...about the Man in the Engine.
我拉开帘幕 我发现了一件事
I pulled back the curtain, and I found out something that,
我想在你们内心深处 你们早已经知道
deep down... I think you all already know.
视察
An inspection!
排好队
Line up!
我叫梅兰妮
My name is Melanie.
你们不认识我 但我代表威尔福德先生
You don't know me, but I speak for Mr. Wilford.
你们曾多次反抗过列车的秩序
You've rebelled against the order of this train many times.
你们的兄弟姐妹
Your brothers and sisters...
死了
have died.
你们的孩子死了
Your children have died.
而你们没有获得任何成绩
And you have nothing to show for it.
我来是想告诉你们
I'm here to tell you,
如果你再次尝试
if you try again,
你还会再度失败
you will fail again.
是扎拉
It's Zarah.
就是她 她就是乔茜
That's her. That's Josie.
不 不
No! No!
放手 别带走她
Let me go! Don't take her!
-叛徒 -乔茜
- Traitor! - Josie!
谢谢你 司闸员
Thank you, Brakeman.
你可以和其他人一起去外面等着了
You can wait outside with the others.
谁来审问她
Who will conduct the interrogation?
你可以走了
You can go now.
我知道你很害怕
I know you're scared.
我想在不伤害你的情况下解决此事
I'd like to resolve this without you getting hurt.
我只想知道莱顿在哪里
I just want to know where Layton is.
这对扎拉来说也很难
It was hard for Zarah, too.
她做了正确的选择 与我们合作
She made the right choice by cooperating,
她也会因此被奖赏
and she'll be rewarded for it.
如果你帮我 我也可以对你一样
If you help me, I can do the same for you.
你还有时间来救自己 乔茜
There's still time to save yourself, Josie.
我知道威尔福德并不存在
I know there's no Wilford.
我还知道你把莱顿放进了抽屉
And I know you put Layton in a drawer
因为他想明白了
because he figured that out,
所以我也知道 你不会放走我的
so I know you won't let me go,
无论你即将向我承诺什么
no matter what you're about to promise.
如果你知道这点
Well, if you know that,
那你应该明白我为什么要找到他
then you know why I need to find him.
你也知道我会不择手段达成目标
And you know I'll do anything necessary to make it happen.
包括利用迈尔斯吗
Including using Miles?
你知道他母亲为了登上这辆火车死了吗
Did you know his mother died getting on this train?
我找到他的时候 他只身一人
He was alone in the world when I found him,
你现在连我都要带走 是吗
and now you're gonna take me, as well?
他现在是我家庭的一份子了
Well, he's part of my family now.
你还可以留在他的生活里
And you can stay in his life
只要你做出对的选择
if you make the right choice.
你所做的一切
All the things you've done,
你所隐瞒的一切
all those things you're hiding --
威尔福德的死亡 谋杀
Wilford's death, murders,
抽屉里的孩子们
children in Drawers.
你肯定有你的理由
You must've had your reasons.
肯定有
You must have.
但你内心肯定也知道
But you have to know, deep down somewhere,
你明白这一切都不对
that none of this is right.
威尔福德先生设计制造了雪国列车
Mr. Wilford engineered Snowpiercer
以特定的方式运转
to function in a certain way.
假如制造它的人是我
If I'd have created it,
我会创造一个不同的世界 更加公平
I would've created a different world, a more just world
但我没有
but I didn't.
我继承了另一个人的创作
I inherited someone else's creation.
人们似乎觉得有权力的人
You know, people seem to think that those in power
不听命于谁
answer to no one
可以随心所欲
they're free to do as they choose.
这完全大错特错
It couldn't be further from the truth.
有权力的人要对每个人负责
The person in power answers to everyone.
我的决定不是因为我想
I make choices not because I want to
而是所有人都这么要求
but because everyone demands it.
这辆列车如此要求
The train demands it.
是什么让你变成了这样
What made you like this?
无论我说什么 你都不会开口是吗
Nothing I say can ever make you talk, can it?
莱顿在哪
Where is Layton?
别这么做 别这么做
Don't do it. Don't do it.
别这么做
Don't do it!
不要
No!
你...
You just...
莱顿在哪
Where's Layton?
他在哪
Where is he?!
求你
Pl-Please...
Please...
保洁员是这列火车上最腐败的工作组
Janitorial is the most corrupt crew on this train.
我们不能相信他
We can't trust him.
我不相信他 但我们需要他
I don't trust him, but we need him.
一个逃犯 一个保洁员和一位老鸨走进酒吧
A fugitive, a janitor, and a madam walked into a bar.
上次我们见面时 特伦斯
Last time we met, Terence,
我们聊到三等厢和车尾
we had a conversation about Third and the Tail.
我记得
I remember.
他的提议
What this guy is proposing
是要掀起腥风血雨
is an awfully bloody business for you.
一定会流血的 特伦斯
There will be blood, Terence.
是的
Yes.
你可怜有钱的前车厢客户会想要你血债血偿的
Your sad, rich clients uptrain will want yours.
梅兰妮·卡维尔今天来找我打听你
Melanie Cavill... came asking about you today.
你跟她说了什么
What'd you tell her?
说如果我看到你
That, if I saw you,
我就会告发你
I'd rat you out.
然后呢
So?
拜托
Come on.
我不会偏心的
I'm not gonna play favorites.
你总有一天会的
You're gonna have to one of these days.
统一舱位
Uniting the classes,
是永远也不会成功的
it just -- it's just never gonna work.
要有决心才行 特伦斯
You gotta want it, Terence.
人们的意愿
Will of the people.
我不想这么冷酷
I don't want to be callous,
但这是数学问题
but it's just math.
而你人数不够
You don't have the numbers.
所以别算上我了
So, count me out.
好
Alright.
该去看看犯人了 让我进去
Time to check the prisoner. Chip me in.
司闸员的职责 你们知道该怎么做
Brakemen's business. You know the drill.
我的天呐
Jesus Christ.
-提尔 -什么事
- Till. - Yeah?
有什么能帮忙的
Yeah, what can I do?
你名叫什么
What's your first name?
贝丝
Bess.
你帮不了任何忙 贝丝
N-Nothing you can do, Bess.
她会回来的
She'll be back.
没事
It's okay.
我什么也没告诉她
I didn't tell her anything.
她不知道你是我们的人
She doesn't know you're one of us.
我是你们的人
I'm one of you.
必须的
You have to be.
我仍然是司闸员 乔茜
I'm still a Brakeman, Josie.
我替你和莱顿做的事 我只是...
What I did for you and Layton, I just --
我那么做是因为关押他不对
I just did it because it wasn't right.
这是你唯一需要的理由
It's the only reason you need.
我仍然要对这辆列车负责
I still have a duty to this train.
我们要对彼此负责
We have a duty to each other...
以及工人
and to the workers
还有我们中最脆弱的人
and to the weakest among us.
没有它就没有未来 贝丝
There's no future without it, Bess.
你得决定什么是对什么是错
You just have to decide what's right and wrong.
结果怎样都不重要
It shouldn't matter what the consequences are for you.
我不知道该怎么帮你
I don't know how to help you.
门外有守卫
There's -- There's Jackboots on the other side,
我也没有解开你手铐的钥匙
and I don't have keys to your cuffs.
-给莱顿传达一条消息 -好
- Get a message to Layton. - Okay.
他藏在奥德丽小姐那里
He's hiding with Miss Audrey.
告诉他扎拉背叛了我们
You tell him that Zarah betrayed us
但我跟迈尔斯联系上了
but I made contact with Miles.
他准备好了
He's ready.
好 我保证
Okay, I promise.
-保证吗 -我保证 我会转告他的
- Promise? - I promise. I will.
好吗
Okay?
贝丝
Bess.
我还需要你做一件事
There's one more thing I need you to do.
梅兰妮 你来了
Melanie, there you are.
我到处找你
Oh, I've been looking everywhere for you.
现在不是时候 露丝
Now is not a good time, Ruth.
头等厢里要出大事了
There's a major problem brewing in First Class.
露丝
Ruth...
不管是什么 都得等 好吗
whatever it is, it needs to wait, okay?
你不明白 是福爵一家
You don't understand. It's the Folgers.
我不管
I don't care.
你明白吗
Do you understand?
我不在乎
I don't give a shit
福爵一家是不是又在抱怨牛排
if the Folgers have another complaint about their Goddamn steak.
没有剩的了 告诉他们 好吗
There's none left! Just tell them that, okay?
这里不是民宿
This isn't a bed-and-breakfast.
这是人类文明的残余
This is the last remnants of humanity.
所以不管是什么 我有真正的问题要处理
So whatever it is, I have real problems.
你做好你的工作 解决这问题
Just do your job and fix it!
当然 梅兰妮
Well, of course, Melanie.
听你安排
Whatever you say.
我
I...
谢谢
Thank you.
我不想继续这样 乔茜
I don't want to continue this, Josie.
你有一个选择
You have a choice.
要莱顿还是迈尔斯
It's Layton or Miles.
你的手
Your hand.
怎么回事
What happened to it?
守卫
Guard!
乘客服务部
梅兰妮
Melanie!
发生了什么
What happened?
怎么不叫上我就去审问
Why did you conduct an interrogation without me?
带她去肥料室
Take her to compost.
这里没事了
We're done here.
莱顿
Layton.
乔茜
Josie.
你好 迈尔斯
Hello, Miles.
听说你今天过得很不顺
I heard you had a rough day.
这家伙很坚强
This guy's a trooper.
完成了练习
Finished his exercises,
跟朋友道别
said goodbye to his friends...
没人干扰
...and no one interfered.
一旦你走进那道门
You know, once you pass through that door,
就没有回头路了
there's no turning back.
你将成为工程师
You'll be an Engineer.
但是在雪国列车上做工程师
But to be an Engineer on Snowpiercer,
你得做出牺牲
you have to make sacrifices.
这有时会很难
And that can be hard.
你做工程师快乐吗
Are you happy as an Engineer?
列车的需求比我们的幸福更重要
The needs of the train are more important than our own happiness.
我们是工程师
We're Engineers.
我们延续着世界的生命
We keep the world alive.
♪出租车司机♪
♪ Taxi driver ♪
♪做我的心理医生♪
♪ Be my shrink for the hour ♪
♪计程表打开♪
♪ Leave the meter running ♪
♪现在是高峰时段♪
♪ It's rush hour ♪
♪穿过大街小巷♪
♪ So take the streets if you wanna ♪
♪只要能跑过魔鬼♪
♪ Just outrun the demons, could you? ♪
♪他说 真主至大♪
♪ He said, "Allahu akbar" ♪
♪我告诉他 别诅咒我♪
♪ I told him, "Don't curse me ♪
♪波波 你需要祷告♪
♪ Bo Bo, you need prayer" ♪
♪它应该伤不了我♪
♪ I guess it couldn't hurt me ♪
♪如果它让我跪下♪
♪ If it brings me to my knees ♪
♪那就是邪教♪
♪ It's a bad religion ♪
♪这单相思♪
♪ Oh, this unrequited love ♪
♪对我来说不过是一个人的崇拜♪
♪ To me, it's nothing but a one-man cult ♪
♪我泡沫塑料杯子里的氰化物♪
♪ And cyanide in my Styrofoam cup ♪
♪我永远无法让他爱我♪
♪ I can never make him love me ♪
♪永远无法让他爱我 爱我♪
♪ Never make him love me, love me ♪
♪爱我 爱我♪
♪ Love me, love me ♪
♪爱我 爱我 爱我♪
♪ Love me, love me, love me ♪
♪爱我 爱我 爱♪
♪ Love me, love me, love ♪
♪出租车司机♪
♪ Taxi driver ♪
♪我发誓我有三条命♪
♪ I swear I got three lives ♪
♪像牛排刀一样悬在我的头顶♪
♪ Balanced on my head like steak knives ♪
♪我不能告诉你我伪装的真相♪
♪ I can't tell you the truth about my disguise ♪
♪我不能相信任何人♪
♪ I can't trust no one ♪
♪他说 真主至大♪
♪ He said, "Allahu akbar" ♪
♪我告诉他 别诅咒我♪
♪ I told him, "Don't curse me ♪
♪波波 你需要祷告♪
♪ Bo Bo, you need prayer" ♪
♪它应该伤不了我♪
♪ I guess it couldn't hurt me ♪
♪如果它让我跪下♪
♪ If it brings me to my knees ♪
你可以进去体验了
We're ready for your experience now.
♪那就是邪教♪
♪ It's a bad religion ♪
♪这单相思♪
♪ This unrequited love ♪
♪对我来说不过是一个人的崇拜♪
♪ To me, it's nothing but a one-man cult ♪
♪我泡沫塑料杯子里的氰化物♪
♪ And cyanide in my Styrofoam cup ♪
-♪我永远无法让他爱我♪ -你好
♪ I can never make him love me ♪ Hello?
♪永远无法让他爱我♪
♪ Never make him love me, no ♪
我今晚可以和谁玩
Who do I get to play with tonight?
是你
You.
我一直在想你
I've been thinking about you...
你有多喜欢肮脏的秘密
...and how much you like dirty, little secrets.
你想知道
How would you like to know...
列车上
the dirtiest little secret
最肮脏的秘密吗
on the whole damn train?